alfred.com 2019-04-10

# Privacy Policy

#### Effective starting: June 1, 2018

Alfred Publishing, LLC (“Alfred Music,” “we,” or “us”) is committed to protecting your privacy and utilizing technology that gives you a powerful and safe online experience. This Privacy Policy applies to the Alfred Publishing, LLC. owned and operated websites and applications and governs data collection and usage. By using the website, you consent to the data practices described in this policy.

We will collect personal data that you submit or which we collect through your use of the website. We may disclose this personal data to Alfred Music's affiliates, customers, and third-party service providers as described in more detail below. We will keep you informed by electronic means about events, products and services that we believe may be of interest to you as a user of the Alfred Music websites. We also use cookies to allow us to provide our services and products. You may review the Privacy Policy in its entirety below.

If you have questions or concerns about our privacy policy or practices, please contact us in the first instance at [customerservice@alfred.com](mailto:customerservice@alfred.com).

The websites[ www.alfred.com.com](http://www.trainingpeaks.com/),[ ](http://www.bestbikesplit.com/)[www.totalsheetmusic.com.com](http://www.totalsheetmusic.com.com/), [www.alfred-music.com](http://www.alfred-music.com/), [www.emtontheweb.com](https://www.emtontheweb.com/), and sionline.alfred.com (hereinafter "the Site") is owned and operated by Alfred Publishing, LLC (“Alfred Music,” “we,” or “us”). The Site provides the ability for users to browse and search through our catalog, place orders, create and view your account information, submit feedback and other customer service inquiries, and engage with our marketing content (the “Services”).

Please read carefully through all sections of this Privacy Policy. Your access to and use of the Site is subject to this Privacy Policy and all applicable laws. By submitting your contact information to receive a quote or more information from us through the Site, or accessing and/or otherwise using the Site, you consent to Alfred Music’s use of your Personal Data as set forth below in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, then you may not use the Site and you should not submit your contact information to the Site. This Privacy Policy may be changed by us from time to time without notice to you, and the governing version will be posted on the Site. Please review this Privacy Policy on a regular basis as your use of the Site will be governed by the then-current Privacy Policy.

Alfred Music recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of our customers and the users of the Site. However, some uses of such information are required for us to conduct legitimate business by providing information of interest to our customers and the users of the Site.

### Notice to California Residents

Except as expressly identified below, we do not disclose a user’s personal data to any third-party for such third-party’s direct marketing purposes. Thus, under California Civil Code Sections 1798.80-1798.84, Alfred Music has no obligation to a California resident to provide further information regarding Owner’s use of the California resident’s personal data.

### Notice to Utah Residents

Except as expressly identified below, we do not disclose a user’s personal data to any third-party for such third-party’s direct marketing purposes.

### What this Privacy Policy Covers

This Privacy Policy covers our treatment of Personal Data that we collect through your use of the Site and when you use Services provided on the Site. This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that we do not own and/or control or to people that we do not employ or manage.

### Our Legal Basis for Collecting, Storing and Processing your Personal Data

If you have created an account to use the Site in order to obtain the Services, we collect, store and process your Personal Data out of a contractual necessity in order to provide you the Services.

In certain cases, we may store and process your Personal Data in order to comply with Alfred Music’s legal obligations for record keeping and other compliance with laws or regulatory compliance.

We obtain your unambiguous consent in order to send electronic marketing materials to provide you information about our products or services that we feel you may be interested in. You may withdraw your consent through the opt-out process included in our emails.

The Personal Data we hold about you is processed by us on the basis of our legitimate interests in providing the Services. Based upon the type and amount of data we collect, we have made a determination that our legitimate interest in using such Personal Data is not outweighed by any detriment to you.

### Information Collection and Use

Through your use of the Services, we may collect the following “Personal Data” from you if you choose to provide it, including:

  * Your name, email, company/school, address and/or telephone number (“Contact Information”).
  * Pages and products viewed, ads that you clicked on, emails from us that you opened, browser type, operating system, IP address and device information, your mobile operating system (OS), a mobile device identifier embedded by us, or other commonly used mobile device identifier if you access the Site on a mobile device (“Analytical Information”).
  * A third party payment processor may collect your credit card information when you place an order for our products (“Financial Information”), which is securely stored and processed by authorize.net. We do not directly store or retain your credit card information. Authorize.net’s privacy policy governing its use of your Financial Information is available at https://www.authorize.net/company/privacy/.
  * We may also collect publicly available information about you from third-party sources, such as the postal service for shipping address verification.

We do not collect any more Personal Data from you than what we have determined is needed for us to provide the Services or that you have decided to share with us to more personalize the Services, and to comply with applicable laws.

### How Your Personal Data May Be Used

We may use Analytical Information to improve the performance or layout of our website and to better administer and troubleshoot our systems.

We may use Contact Information and other Personal Data to provide you the Services on the Site; to evaluate and improve the Services; to fulfill your requests for information; and to contact you about Alfred Music products or services and those of our affiliates, based on the preferences you have indicated.

We provide you the opportunity to consent to receive commercial email from us related to the Services or information that we deem you may be interested in when you seek more information from us. We will give you the opportunity to "opt out" of receiving any unsolicited information from us or to limit the unsolicited information you receive from us to information regarding the Services or information you specifically request or information we determine you may find useful as a result of your use of the Site.

### Information Sharing and Disclosure

Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, we will not share your Personal Data with any other person or company. We will share your Personal Data to other companies or people when:

  * We need to share your information to provide a product or service you have requested;
  * We need to send the information to companies who work on behalf of Alfred Music to provide a product or service to you. Unless we tell you differently, we only provide these companies the minimum amount of information that is necessary for them to assist us and these companies do not have any right to use the Personal Data we provide to them beyond what is necessary to assist us;
  * We find that your actions on our website violate the Terms and Conditions of Use, any of our usage guidelines for specific services or any agreement; and
  * As required to respond to or initiate subpoenas, court orders, or legal process.

### Third Party Processors

To ensure that your Personal Data receives an adequate level of protection, we have put in place appropriate procedures with the third parties we share your Personal Data with to ensure that your Personal Data is treated by those third parties in a way that is consistent with and which respects the applicable laws on data security and privacy.

### How long do we keep your information?

We will store your information for as long as you have an account with Alfred Music. We may keep records of transactions with you for a period of up to seven (7) years to comply with the IRS requirements.

### Use of Cookies

We use “cookies,” a small text file transferred to your device, along with similar technologies (e.g., internet tag technologies, web beacons, embedded scripts) to help provide you a better, more personalized user experience. For a detailed description of the cookies we use and your ability to control the use of cookies while you navigate the internet, please see our [[Cookies Policy]](https://web.archive.org/cookies-policy).

### Interest-Based Ads

Unaffiliated third parties may use cookies and other technologies on our website to collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites you visit in order to provide you with interest-based advertising. You can generally opt-out of receiving interest-based advertisements from members of the Network Advertising Initiative or the Digital Advertising Alliance by visiting their opt-out pages: (<http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>) and (<http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>). When you opt-out using these links, please note that you may still receive advertisements. They just will not be personalized based on your interests.

### Do Not Track

Some internet browsers incorporate a “Do Not Track” feature that signals to websites you visit that you do not want to have your online activity tracked. Given that there is not a uniform way that browsers communicate the “Do Not Track” signal, the Site does not currently interpret, respond to or alter its practices when it receives “Do Not Track” signals.

### Notice to Residents of Europe and the United Kingdom

Under the GDPR, you have the following rights related to Alfred Music use of your Personal Data.

  * Right to withdraw consent. You have the right to notify Alfred Music that you no longer want us to process or use your Personal Data. You can do that by contacting Alfred Music at the email or mailing address below.
  * Right to data portability. You have the right to obtain a copy of your Personal Data stored and processed by Alfred Music and direct Alfred Music to transfer your Personal Data to another controller via csv format.
  * Right to erasure/Right to be forgotten. You have the right to request that any of your Personal Data being stored or processed by Alfred Music is deleted from our records. However, while we can delete your Personal Data from our current records, copies of your data may be stored in Alfred Music’s inactive and archived records and will be deleted in accordance with Alfred Music’s then-current document management policy. In some cases, your Personal Data may be continued to be stored in archived records of transactions or activities where Owner is required by law to retain such records.
  * Right to restriction of processing. You may request that Alfred Music restrict the processing of your Personal Data. In such case, this may affect your ability to use or navigate the Site.

To exercise any of your rights above, please contact Alfred Music at [customerservice@alfred.com](mailto:customerservice@alfred.com) or PO Box 10003, Van Nuys, CA 91410. If you choose to exercise any of your rights listed above, it may affect your ability to use the Site, as the operation and functionalities provided on the Site may require the use of your Personal Data.

### Ability to Review and Edit Your Information

You may review and approve the Contact Information about you that was stored in our database and obtained through your use of the Site. Upon your written request, we will remove that information from our database or change or correct personal data that you state is erroneous within applicable regulatory or other legal requirements. You should understand, however, that information about you in our database might come from a number of sources.

### Security

We will take reasonable and appropriate measures to protect your Personal Data  from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction, taking into due account the risks involved in the processing and the nature of the personal data. However, no electronic storage method or data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

### Commitment to Children’s Privacy

In compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, 15 U.S.C., §§ 6501-06 and 16 C.F.R., §§ 312.1-312.12, the Site does not collect information from children under 13 years of age, and we do not intentionally collect information from persons under sixteen (16) years of age. Use of the Site is limited to users that are sixteen (16) years of age and older. By using the Site, you represent that you are sixteen (16) years of age or older.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to change, modify or otherwise update this policy at any time. These changes or updates will be effective immediately. We may provide you notice of such changes when they are material, such notice may be given by posting on the Site, by electronic or conventional mail or by any other means by which you obtain notice of the changes or updates.

### Policies of Other Websites

The Site may contain links to third-party websites not owned or controlled by Alfred Music. Alfred Music is not responsible for the privacy policies of any third-party websites which user may access through a third?party link. Further, these third-party websites may have privacy policies that differ from this Privacy Policy. Alfred Music disclaims all responsibility for the privacy practices of such other third-party websites. You should read the privacy policies of each third-party website you visit to determine what information each third-party website may be collecting about you and how they intend to use such information.

### Questions

If you have any questions or comments about these Terms of Use or this Site, please contact us by email at [customerservice@alfred.com](mailto:customerservice@alfred.com). You also may write to us at:

Alfred Music  
Attn: Privacy  
PO Box 10003  
Van Nuys, CA 91410
